Falco. Where are you
headed this late?
Left something at HQ,
so I'm running back there
to grab it real quick.
See you later!
Falco, could you do me a favor?
Sure. What do you need?
I want to send a letter, but
coming from the internment zone,
it'll probably be checked, right?
Yeah, probably.
If they see what I wrote,
they'll know I shouldn't be here.
Would you be willing to send it
from outside the internment zone?
Sure thing. Guess this
is to your family?
Yeah. Just letting
them know that I'm here
and that I'm all right.
Hm? Hey. Why all the commotion?
The Tybur family just arrived.
Looks like all of them.
Excuse me?
They're the Tyburs' personal guard.
It's an independent force.
I hear they're good.
Please come in.
Sorry to drop in unannounced.
I'm Willy. Head of
the Tyburs. It's a pleasure.
I lead Marley's Warrior Unit.
Commander Theo Magath.
It is an honor to make your
acquaintance, Lord Tybur.
The feeling's mutual, Commander Magath.
Now then. Allow me to introduce
you to my beloved family.
I told you to stay still!
Let him go!
Now look what you've done!
You've overseen the
Warrior unit quite successfully,
Commander, so I'm curious.
Can you tell which of us
is the War Hammer Titan?
No, sir. I've seen
no sign at all.
Frankly, I'm not even sure if
the War Hammer came here with you.
You have an
astute mind. As I'd heard.
But no. It is here.
Someone among us wields the War Hammer.
I came here to lay eyes
on the statue of Helos.
It captures the moment, a century ago,
when a mere human struck down
the Devil of All Earth,
saving the world and becoming a hero.
What a grand sight.
He stands brave and beautiful.
Not a scratch on him.
Truly. This is
the spirit of Marley.
Yes, I agree with you.
Especially since the
statue's completely hollow.
You're an unsparing critic, Commander.
I'm told that you've been
working to reinstate
conscription among Marleyan citizens.
To the people of Marley,
war exists only in the
pages of their newspapers.
They read words saying
that the border's expanded,
and they feel pride.
If it's our tamed devils,
or conscripts from conquered nations
that bleed for those lands,
so much the better.
I suppose the hope is that
by forcing Marleyan citizens
to risk their own necks in the trenches,
then we can eventually
put a halt to this nation's
self-destructive march toward war.
But if I had the ear of the man
controlling Marley from the shadows,
I would tell him it's too late.
You truly don't hold back, do you?
What am I to say?
As you just noted,
Marley is under the
Tybur family's influence.
But we did not set Marley
on this path of militarism.
The nation chose that for itself.
Long ago, we Tyburs gave Marley freedom
and power by way of atonement.
We chose to stand by and watch
as this country plunged
itself into darkness.
We intend to reveal
everything to the world
during the main event of the festival.
When I said I'd come to see
the hero's statue, I meant it.
Marley needs a new Helos.
Theo Magath.
I ask you to take my hand
and work at my side.
Good morning, Pock!
Hey, Pieck.
Why are you down there?
I guess this just feels
more natural to me.
Sorry if I scared you.
Would'ja please just walk normal?
Most Titans come from the south,
so Paradis' defenses are heaviest there,
and comparatively sparse
towards the northern mountains.
I see. So we should
attack from the north.
It's worth considering at least.
However, we need to land a great
many troops and supplies,
and for our largest ships to dock,
we'll need control of
that southern wharf.
Then we should come from the south.
Not necessarily.
We'd be sailing straight to the spot
where we lost our scout ships.
Its where the enemy's focused.
They might've even torn the wharf down.
All right. Then what are
you trying to say?
I was just sharing
information that I thought
you might find useful, sir.
Well, I think you've shared quite enough.
I don't know why we let an
Eldian talk in the first place.
The Paradis plan
seems to be coming right along.
The brass in charge is oh so intelligent.
I sure am excited to hear
what they come up with.
Like entrusting the whole operation
to four children with no support?
Hm?
He's winning.
Falco just passed Gabi.
Heh. Look how they
celebrate that one win.
Dumb kids. Ignorance
really is bliss.
But it doesn't matter how well Falco does
from this point, does it?
I mean Gabi's so far ahead of him.
Did you see how he
took off at the last stretch?
Hey there, kids.
What's all the fuss about?
Falco finally got the best of Gabi!
Really? He beat her grades?
No. He just
outran her in a race.
Sure, but it's still a historic feat!
Hey. Can you cut it out?
Seriously, it's embarrassing.
Pretty impressive!
It sounds like maybe you're
gonna be the next Armor!
There's no point in
trying to beat me now,
it's too little too late!
In case you forgot, I heroically defended
our motherland in battle!
Yeah, I know, but there's still a chance.
They haven't announced
a successor quite yet,
and until they do,
I'll keep on working my hardest.
All right. Said like
a professional Warrior.
Your brother's inheriting the Beast,
so you and your family'll be made
Honorary Marleyans no matter what you do!
You know that, so why try so hard?
I'm doing this for you!
Falco...
He really just up and said it!
Huh?! You're trying to stop me
from getting what I want
but you think you're doing it for me?
That doesn't make any damn sense!
He couldn't get through to her.
Huh? What's that jerk's problem?
Hey! Tell me!
Well if it isn't our brave young
Warriors-in-training.
Gabi!
I heard what you did, Gabi!
You're a hero to all
us Eldians, you know that?
Thanks for your service!
Sorry, but I'm just Zofia.
Huh?
Stop that, you stupid lush!
Between the day-drinking and
the grabbing onto random girls,
I've had it up to here with you!
Shut up, you nosy old bat!
Ain't nothing wrong with
givin' a hero due praise!
There wouldn't be, except getting praised
by someone like you is bad luck!
Now go! Drag yourself home
to your poor mother!
Now. Allow me to give
you kids a nice treat.
Eat up, okay?
I want you to get big and
strong like Vice Chief Braun!
Thank you so much!
Whoa. Are they
really gonna declare war
from here in the internment zone?
Looks like they're building a stage.
They say leaders are gonna come from
all over the world, and by
the time this festival is over,
they're all gonna be on our side.
Fantastic!
Sounds like all of Marley's problems
are about to magically disappear!
You really don't think it'll work?
Do you really think it will?
We've been at war with
too many of these countries.
They want Marley to fall.
We aren't treated well here,
but compared to the hatred
that Eldians face abroad,
we're actually lucky.
My family came from
a foreign internment zone.
It was awful.
Well. That's all the more reason
why we have to do something.
They chose to meet
at the internment zone.
Maybe they wanna help
people understand us.
This is our chance to show the
world that we aren't devils.
Okay, but how?
Smile! I know how
badly you wanna be right,
but right now, you can't be.
Help prove yourself wrong
or we're all screwed.
You shape up, too.
Stop pretending to be a weirdo, Zofia.
Um. This is just who I am.
Fine. So what
are you gonna fix?
Huh? There's nothing for
me to fix, I'm perfect.
I'm sharp as a needle
and cute as a button.
And when I captivate all the VIPs,
my spot's gonna be that much more secure.
Are you sure you're not a devil?
And if you two ever cheer
for Falco over me again,
I will make you cry.
Oh, she's definitely a devil.
It's Commander Magath.
Here.
Hmm. Is such a large-scale
demolition necessary?
Much of the structure has
decayed beyond repair.
Allow me to congratulate you.
The army is now yours, General.
No, sir. It belongs
to the nation.
And Marley is a nation commanded
by none other than you, Lord Tybur.
Hm. This nation
isn't mine, though.
It belongs to the people:
Marleyan and Eldian.
Now that I have the wheel,
I can see why no one's
tried to turn it before.
It's too heavy.
I want nothing more than to let it go,
but the time has come when I must not.
It just happened to be me.
By sheer chance, I happened to
be the man that fate turned to.
The house was on the verge of collapse,
but a few of its pillars remain usable.
And according to them, the house
is already infested with rats.
Nicely done, Falco.
It's thanks to what
you said, Mr. Kruger!
Honestly, I doubt I'll catch up to Gabi,
no matter how hard I push myself.
But even so, I'm gonna
keep moving forward.
I see.
I would still say that
I'm in your debt though.
Thank you for delivering
those letters for me.
You've been a big help.
Huh? Oh, sure.
That glove. Did your
family send it to you?
They thought it would make
hospital life less boring.
It's hard to do much in this shape, but
I need to move forward, too.
After the festival,
I'm going back to my hometown.
Glad to hear it.
A doctor's coming.
Well. I should head out.
Yeah.
Would you mind if I sit next to you?
Sure. Why not?
Thanks, I appreciate it.
My name's Jaeger. I'm an
Internment Zone physician.
I like to come out here and
drink tea from time to time.
Good to meet you. I'm Kruger.
Good to meet you, too.
I saw you speaking with a boy
just now. Is he a friend?
Guess so.
Hmm. I wonder
if he could've been my friend.
After all, I too sit here,
looking for someone to talk to.
Before the Eldian
Restorationists were caught,
that boy's uncle was a leading member.
Marley sends captured restorationists
straight to paradise,
frequently with their family's in tow.
In order to protect their loved ones,
the boy and his brother said
they wanted to become Warriors.
And now, his brother has been chosen
to inherit the Beast Titan.
Which means the Grice family
is finally safe again.
Hold on. Why tell me all this?
So that you'll stop asking that young man
to run errands for you.
The Grice family's efforts
will have been for nothing
if people begin to suspect
him of something illicit.
And if your heart and mind
truly are healthy,
you should go back to your family now.
The people you love
won't always be waiting.
If you take them for granted,
you will be left with regret.
Will I? I see.
You have regrets about your own family?
I'm filled with them. Even now.
I was so hard on my son.
So insistent that he become a doctor.
That's why he took his sister
outside the walls.
That's why she...
She...
It's
my fault. It's all my fault!
Mr. Jaeger!
Please don't go outside unsupervised!
Sorry about this. I only
looked away for a moment.
Come along, Mr. Jaeger.
Everything will be all right.
This is crazy.
I've seen these people in the papers.
Enough idle chitchat.
We're gonna serve these people
so well that their heads spin.
Look, they're starting
to leave dirty dishes.
Get 'em!
Yes.
I've always felt that way.
Falco, drink!
Here!
Huh? Look. They're letting some
filthy-blood carry our plates.
Ugh. No wonder
the food here reeks.
I-I'm terribly sorry, ma'am!
Shh! Don't make a scene of it.
But the wine.
It stained your outfit.
My lady. Is everything
all right?
This is quite embarrassing,
but I spilled wine on my kimono
and was just asking
this boy for assistance.
Thank you, young man.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Please come right this way.
Wh-Why would you...?
There's no telling what
they would've done to you
if I'd been honest, right?
Are you okay?
Yeah. She saved me.
Even though she knew that I'm an Eldian.
I think I know why.
That woman's probably
an Easterner from Hizuru.
It's Willy Tybur!
Willy!
If it isn't the heir of our saviors!
Ambassador Ogweno!
Long time no see!
And Nambia! It's been
since we were children.
Yes. Sorry for
all the times I made you cry.
I wonder if you remember this, Willy.
Oh! Of course, from when
you fell out of that tree!
Let me bid you a warm welcome
and offer my thanks to
you all for traveling so far.
Until very recently,
some of us were engaged
in a rather unseemly
dispute over resources.
However, yesterday's enemy
is today's enemy!
Pardon.
I mean yesterday's enemy
is today's friend!
Let us wash the past down the toilet
alongside our drinks tonight!
Toward that end,
please raise your glasses
and join me for a toast!
Cheers! To everlasting peace!
Such a refined joke!
It's unfortunate that
this isn't a first language
for all our guests.
You weren't quite understood.
So please, allow me
to take over from here.
Thanks for breaking the ice, Ambassador.
All right, Willy!
Kin of our saviors!
You've been invited to join me tomorrow,
in the Liberio Internment Zone.
It is home to a people whose
blood runs through my own veins.
These people are known
to be descendants of devils,
for their ancestors
massacred untold millions.
And strangely, after enduring
the worst of their cruelty,
Marley used those devils
to oppress other nations,
repeating the horrors of the past.
Would the world not be better
if Titans ceased to exist?
There is but one answer
to the Eldian question.
After years of searching, I've found it.
And tomorrow night, I'll share it
in the course of my first-ever
theatrical production.
I hope that each of you will be there.
Now. To the playwrights
and the witnesses of history!
To the playwrights
What the hell?
What is all this?
Gabi!
About time you woke up!
Why is everything all crazy?
It's for the festival!
Different people have been pouring in
from outside all morning,
and they opened up
a bunch of food stalls!
Here, try this!
It's the best thing I've ever tasted!
Let's go!
Ugh. It hurts!
That's what you get for being a glutton.
Look at the flags they put up!
They should just
make every day a festival.
Think so, huh?
It probably  nothing, but I've
noticed a lot of new things
have been happening in the last few days.
Is that right?
It feels strange.
As if the world is about to
change in a big way.
Yeah. I hear you.
Hey. How've you
enjoyed the festival?
Wait. Where's Falco?
Oh. He said he saw someone
he knew in the crowd
and ran off to say hi.
Huh. Hope this doesn't
make him late.
Man. You really can't loosen up
without booze, can you?
Look at all these people.
Look there. I guess
he made it back.
Mr. Braun!
Where the hell have you been?
Sir. Do you mind coming with me?
Don't think there's time.
Ah, you'll be fine.
The curtains won't go up
for a few more minutes.
Over this way!
What's this about, Falco?
You can see for yourself in a second.
It's through this door!
okay...
I got him to come!
Evening. It's been
four years... Reiner.
Eren!
Reiner faces Eren in
the gloom of a lamplit cellar.
As Willy Tybur sweeps
his audience to their feet,
Eren confesses.
He and Reiner are the same.
Next episode:
"Declaration of War."